(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-30T20:27:41.326324",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
君に 会いたい時だって どこか 会えない気持ちがある
Even when I want to see you, somewhere I feel like I can't meet you.
だけど 本当の優しさが そこにあるかも知れない
But true kindness might be right there.
人混みに 揺られてる どこかに 当てがあるわけじゃない
Swaying in the crowd, it's not like I have a destination.
独りきり 歩いても 何か 解決することじゃない
Even if I walk all alone, it's not something that solves anything.
自分が 本当に望んでる 気持ちは きっと
The feeling I truly desire is surely...
これから 二人で 歩いて行くことさ
Walking together from now on.
君に 会いたい時だって どこか 会えない気持ちがある
Even when I want to see you, somewhere I feel like I can't meet you.
だけど 本当の優しさが そこにあるかも知れない
But true kindness might be right there.
二人 輝いた季節は きっと これからも続いてく
The season we both shined in will surely continue from now on.
だから 大切な未来に この想いを 残したい
That's why I want to leave these feelings in a precious future.
飽きるまで 話しても 全部 分かり合えるわけじゃない
Even if we talk until we're tired of it, we won't understand everything.
言葉より 伝えたい 気持ちが この胸にあふれてる
Feelings I want to convey more than words overflow in my heart.
君が いつか 探した夢の 続きは きっと
The continuation of the dream you searched for someday is surely...
二人で 描いて行こう 忘れないで
Let's draw it together, don't forget.
独りきり 孤独なようで 皆 何かに悩んでいる
Though feeling all alone and lonely, everyone is worried about something.
すぐには 変わらないけれど とにかく 信じていたい
It won't change right away, but anyway I want to believe in it.
流した 涙捨てた上で ずっと 君のそばで生きたい
After shedding and discarding tears, I want to live forever by your side.
いつか 振り返った時に 後悔したくないから
Because when I look back someday, I don't want to have any regrets.
君に
To you,
会いたいと言いたくて
Wanting to say I want to see you,
ふたり
The two of us
輝いた季節は
The shining season
ふたり
The two of us
後悔したくないから
Because I don't want to have any regrets,
ふたり
The two of us
叶わない夢なんて
Dreams that won't come true,
簡単には口にはしたくない
I don't want to say so easily.
諦めた瞬間に
The moment you give up,
自分自身 終わらせてるだけ
You're just ending it yourself.
もっと単純に感じたい
I want to feel more simply,
君のこと いつも素直に笑うよ
I want to always smile honestly at you.
未来は続いてく
The future continues on.
君がホントにスキだって
That I truly love you,
いつも心に飾っていたい
I always want to keep decorated in my heart.
楽しいだけが全てなら
If only having fun is everything,
本当の愛じゃないから
That's not true love.
会いたいと言いたくて
Wanting to say I want to see you,
ふたり 輝いた季節は
The season where the two of us shone,
きっとこれからも続いてく
Will surely continue from now on.
だから 大切な未来にこの想いを残したい
That's why I want to leave these feelings in a precious future.
会いたいと言いたくて
Wanting to say I want to see you,
ふたり 輝いた季節は
The season where the two of us shone,
きっとこれからも続いてく
Will surely continue from now on.
みんな6周年ライブに来てくれてありぺこ！
Everyone, thank you for coming to the 6th anniversary live, Peko!
そして大変お待たせしました！
And sorry to keep you waiting!
けどね、みんなに楽しんでもらえるようなライブになってるぺこだから、
But you know, it's a live you can all enjoy, Peko,
ぜひともお楽しみに！
So please look forward to it!
そして1曲目はそこに歌わしてもらったぺこ！
And the first song might have been right there, Peko!
まっ、ていうことは今回のテーマは、そう！パチスロ第2弾！イェーイ！
Well, that means the theme this time is, that's right! The 2nd Pachislot! Yay!
当たり演出もね、めちゃめちゃいろいろありますんで、ぜひとも次の曲は何来るかなって考えながら楽しんでもらえたら嬉しいぺこ！
There are tons of different winning effects too, so I'd be happy if you enjoy wondering what song comes next!
そして今回のハッシュタグはこちら！うさだぺこら6周年記念ライブぺこなんで、たくさんポストしてください！
And the hashtag this time is right here! Since it's the Usada Pekora 6th Anniversary Live Peko, please post a lot!
ちゅうわけで、早速回していくかん！
Anyway, let's get right to spinning it!
運命の一撃
A Fateful Strike
好機 好機 好機
Chance, chance, chance
笑うべきだと分かったときは泣くべきじゃねえぺこ！
When you know you should be laughing, you shouldn't be crying, Peko!
運命の一撃を叩き込め！
Deliver a fateful strike!
咲かすか 枯らすか 現在
Whether blooming or withering, now
燃えるように 陽が沈む
The burning sun sets
歯車が回る
The gears turn
ラッパが鳴れば 着火様々
If the trumpet sounds, it ignites, varied and many
待った無しの 物語
A story that won't wait
発車バラバラ 滑車ガタガタ
Departure is scattered, the pulley rattles
真っ赤な過去が 追いかける
The bright red past chases after
道化師の笑み
A clown's smile
仮面の裏側
On the back of the mask
どう消しても 消えない
Even if you erase it, it won't disappear
傷が痛んでも
Even if the scars ache
咲かすか 枯らすか 現在
Whether blooming or withering, now
燃えるように 陽が沈む
The burning sun sets
真夜中の暗い 孤独から
I'll set out from the deep loneliness of midnight
繰り出す 冴え渡る鐘が
The faintly echoing bell
響く日々の一歩先へ
Toward the place where the sound rings
ラッパが鳴れば 着火わらわら
If the trumpet sounds, it ignites, swarming
待った無しの 演目の応酬
An exchange of performances that won't wait
真っ赤幕の間
In the midst of the bright red curtain
落下はまだか 真っ逆さま
Is the fall still ahead? Hanging upside down
待ちわびる骸に 足を掴まれ
Grabbed by the feet, down to the abyss
奈落の底まで 呻呼思想も忘れて
Ah, forgetting even my thoughts
息も出せない
I can't even breathe
咲かすか 枯らすか 現在
Whether blooming or withering, now
眠るように 目を閉じる
Closing my eyes as if asleep
身体中巡る 猛毒から
Should I escape from the deadly poison?
逃げ出すか 冴え渡る鐘に
Will you live listening to the bell?
耳を澄ませ 生きるのか
Choose one, come on!
どちらか選べさあ
Like a bud waiting to bloom
開花を待つ芽のように
You just have to think about the future
未来だけ想えばいい
Erase the ghosts of the past
過去の亡霊を消して
Whether blooming or withering, now
咲かすか 枯らすか 現在
燃えるように 陽が沈む
The burning sun sets
真夜中の暗い 孤独から
I'll set out from the deep loneliness of midnight
運命が壊れるような声で叫べ
Shout with a voice that sounds like fate is breaking
始まりの合図 幕開けさ
The signal for the beginning, curtain opens
舞って踊るさ
I'll dance as I wait
誰しも最期には涙流す
Everyone sheds tears in the end
だからいまは堪え進む
That's why I endure and move forward now
幕が降りるその時まで
Until the moment the curtain falls
まだ絶えず 歯車が回る
The gears still turn endlessly
開花を待つ芽のように
Like a bud waiting to bloom
未来だけ想えばいい
You just have to think about the future
過去の亡霊を消して
Erase the ghosts of the past
咲かすか 枯らすか 現在
Whether blooming or withering, now
燃えるように 陽が沈む
The burning sun sets
真夜中の暗い 孤独から
I'll set out from the deep loneliness of midnight
繰り出す 運命が
Out of the loneliness, fate
壊れるような声で叫べ
Shout with a voice that breaks
始まりの合図 幕開けさ
The signal for the beginning, the curtain rises
舞って踊るさ
Dancing and spinning
誰しも最期には涙流す
Everyone sheds tears in the end
だからいまは堪え進む
That's why I push forward now
幕が降りるその時まで
Until the moment the curtain falls
まだ絶えず 歯車が回る
The gears still turn endlessly
ココロが止まらない
My heart won't stop
感じている
Feeling it deep inside
何かをするのに
To do something
理由なんかいらないね
You don't need any reason at all
何かをするのに理由なんかいらないね
You don't need a reason to do something, do you?
熱くなるよ 君を見ているだけで
It gets hot just looking at you.
戦っているのよ 期待はどんな時でも
You're fighting, aren't you? No matter when, I'm waiting.
もつれて 迷い込む
Tangled up, losing my way,
イチかバチか 夢に向かい 加速する
An all-or-nothing rush accelerating toward a dream.
ココロが止まらない 感じている
My heart won't stop, I can feel it.
悩み多き日常のターンに
In the turns of these worry-filled days,
君がいる時の自分が一番好きだよ
the version of myself when I'm with you is the one I like best.
ココロは止まらない 光の中
My heart won't stop, in the light,
七色の水しぶきあげて
Raising a seven-colored spray of water,
新しい明日の風に向かい 走り出そうよ
let's run toward the wind of a new tomorrow.
二人っきりで
Just the two of us.
逢いたい 気持ちがため息に溶けていく
The feelings of wanting to meet you melt into my sighs.
淋しい夜はそばにいてくれた
You stayed by my side on lonely nights.
泣き出しそうになった時 気づかないふりをしてくれたね
When I was about to burst into tears, you pretended not to notice.
重ねる口唇からこぼれる せつなさも 愛しさも
The sorrow and the love that spill from our overlapping lips.
ココロが止まらない 感じている
My heart won't stop, I can feel it.
もっと全てを変えてみたい
I want to change everything even more.
願った奇跡がこんなにも近くにあったよ
The miracle I wished for was so close to me.
ココロは止まらない 通りすぎた
My heart won't stop, the summer scent
夏のにおい なつかしいね
that passed by, it's nostalgic.
君を好きになってから 前より淋しがり屋になってしまった
Since I fell in love with you, I've become more lonely than before.
こわいものはたった1つ
There's only one thing I'm afraid of:
君が優しすぎること
you being too kind.
たそがれが風とめても 夢へのブレーキかからない
Even if twilight stops the wind, the brakes for the dream won't catch.
ココロが止まらない 感じている
My heart won't stop, I can feel it.
きっと答えは1つじゃない
The answer certainly isn't just one.
君に逢うためだけに とてもやさしくなれるよ
Only to meet you, I can become very kind.
ココロは止まらない 月の雫
My heart won't stop, drops of the moon.
ずっと君を探してた
I had been looking for you the whole time.
同じ時 同じ星見上げて このままずっと 色あせぬように
Looking up at the same stars at the same time, I hope it will surely stay like this, so it won't fade.
輝くマリンブルー やっと出会えたからさ
Shining Marine Blue, since we finally met
ミラクルマリンパワー せーので飛び込もう
Miracle Marine Power, let's jump in on the count of three!
Go! Go! Let's Go! SEA STORY!
輝くマリンブルー
Shining Marine Blue,
やっと出会ったサマータイム
at last, the summer time we met.
ミラクルマリンパワー
Miracle Marine Power,
「せーの」で飛び込もう！
Let's dive in on the count of three!
Go! Go! Let's Go! SEA STORY!
太陽さんさん裸足で
Barefoot under the sun,
かけ出していこうビーチへ
let's dash off to the beach!
ココナッツ冒険
A coconut adventure,
見つけに行こう海のワンダーランド
let's go find it in the ocean's wonderland.
みんな歌えば（歌おう）
If everyone sings (Sing along),
イルカがジャンプ（高く）
dolphins jump (Higher!),
カニとタコのダンス（ワンツー）
crabs and octopuses dance (One-two!).
スペシャルな夢を描こう！
Let's paint a special dream!
輝くマリンブルー
Shining Marine Blue,
やっと出会ったサマータイム
at last, the summer time we met.
ミラクルマリンパワー
Miracle Marine Power,
「せーの」で飛び込もう！
Let's dive in on the count of three!
Go! Go! Let's Go! SEA STORY!
海底探検泳いで
Exploring the deep sea floor,
一緒に遊びに行こうよ
let's go play together.
笑顔が何よりの
A smile is more than anything,
たった一つの宝物だよ
truly the one and only treasure.
シャチの背中に（乗って）
On the orca's back (Ride on),
サンゴのトンネル（抜けて）
through the conch tunnel (Slip through),
クラゲのリズム（ワンツー）
to the jellyfish rhythm (One-two!).
始まる夢のステージ！
The dream stage begins!
きらめくマリンスノー
Shining Marine Snow,
みんな一緒にevery day
let's enjoy every day together.
スペシャルサマーソング
A special summer song,
「せーの」で始めよう！
let's start on the count of three!
Go! Go! Let's Go! SEA STORY!
輝くマリンブルー
Shining Marine Blue,
やっと出会ったサマータイム
at last, the summer time we met.
ミラクルマリンパワー
Miracle Marine Power,
「せーの」で飛び込もう！
Let's dive in on the count of three!
グレートマリンブルー
Great Marine Blue,
水平線の彼方まで
to the edge of the horizon.
ミラクルマリンパワー
Miracle Marine Power,
「せーの」で飛び込もう！
Let's dive in on the count of three!
Go! Go! Let's Go! SEA STORY!
きらめくマリンスノー
Shining Marine Snow,
みんな一緒にevery day
let's enjoy every day together.
スペシャルサマーソング
A special summer song,
「せーの」で始めよう！
let's start on the count of three!
Go! Go! Let's Go! SEA STORY!
輝くマリンブルー
Shining Marine Blue,
やっと出会ったサマータイム
at last, the summer time we met.
ミラクルマリンパワー
Miracle Marine Power,
「せーの」で飛び込もう！
Let's dive in on the count of three!
グレートマリンブルー
Great Marine Blue,
水平線の彼方まで
to the edge of the horizon.
ミラクルマリンパワー
Miracle Marine Power,
「せーの」で飛び込もう！
Let's dive in on the count of three!
真っ赤な薔薇はあいつの唇
Bright red roses are that one's lips,
やさしく抱きしめてくれないと眠る
gently holding me close, begging me to sleep.
瞳の奥に獲物を映して
Reflecting prey in the depths of the eyes,
寂しく問いかける愛の在りか
lonely, I ask where love resides.
男には自分の世界がある
A man has his own world;
たとえるなら空をかけるひと筋の流れ星
if you compare it to a single shooting star racing across the sky.
背中で泣いている 男の美学
A man crying in silence on his back
真珠の色は あいつのまなざし
The color of the emerald in his gaze
遥かな幸せを 夢に描く
Painting distant happiness in his dreams
いためることを 恐れるあまりに
For fear of hurting
冷たく突き放す 愛もあるさ
Sometimes there is also cold love
男には 自分の世界がある たとえるなら
Men have their own world, like...
風をはらい 荒くるう稲光
A breeze that dishevels the air
都会の闇に 体を溶かして
Melt his body in the darkness
背中で泣いている 男の美学
A man crying in silence on his back
Amazing grace! How sweet the sound That saved a wretch like me!
I once was lost, but now am found; Was blind, but now I see.
女アタック 突入！
Woman Attack, breach!
いざ勝負！
Now for the showdown!
しゃーるべこら！
Let's go, Pekora!
いざ勝負！
Now for the showdown!
勝利！
Victory!
闘志の章
[Title: Chapter of Fighting Spirit]
夜をさまよふ 影が 光を裂こうと吠える
Shadows wandering the night howl to tear the light.
罪深き羊たちよ 容赦はしません
O sinful sheep, show no mercy.
守るべき人のため 優しい心のなかに
For the sake of those to protect, within a gentle heart...
御意に！ 命懸けて 接戦を！ 戦場へ、翔けて
At your will! Risking lives in a close fight! Soar into the battlefield!
狂い咲けよ 咲き誇れ 闘志の華よ
Bloom wildly, bloom in pride, O flowers of fighting spirit!
戦の地に降り立つ夢
A dream of stepping down onto the battlefield,
大輪の炎 闇を蹴散らして
kicking away the darkness with a great blossom of flame.
勝利を 勇気と熱を 縦に掴め
Seize victory with courage and passion as your shield!
連れて行こう 辿り着く 金色の空
Let's go forth, reaching the golden sky.
笑顔を育む大地へ
To the land that nurtures smiles,
夜はいずれ去り 朝が訪れる
night will eventually depart and morning will come.
全てを越えて 君の愛 叶う
Surpassing everything, your love will come true.
星の巡りを辿り
Following the movement of the stars,
手にした希望の十字
the cross of hope we obtained in our hands.
後悔などしないわ
There's no such thing as regret—
救いは私が与える
salvation is what I bestow.
悪仕掛けの悪 踊れよ
Dance, you elaborately engineered evil!
光が弾き舞い 遊ぶはお暇死まい
Light dances and plays, playtime is over!
大胆無敵な技 目指す場所は 勝利の扉 開く砲 命生まれる楽園
Bold and invincible techniques, where we aim is the door to victory and the paradise where life is born.
さあ共に行きましょう
Come, let's go together.
正義は必ず勝つ いつでも
Justice will always win, no matter what.
空を渡る 溢れ出し燃える想いが
Overflowing, burning feelings crossing the sky
鮮やかに彩る虹へ
to the rainbow brilliantly adorned.
瞳を交わして 絆を結べば
Exchanging glances and forging bonds,
見えてくる 新しい朝が
a new morning comes into view.
時を越えて 暁の幸せはほら 誰の上にも降り注ぐ
Crossing time, look, the happiness of dawn pours down upon everyone.
雨の中を 雨はやがて止め 渇きを癒すよ
In the rain, the rain will soon stop and heal the thirst.
過去を解き放て 君の夢を問う
Unleash the past, asking for your dream.
貴方と想いを 数えきれないほどの 出会いと別れ重ねて
Piling up countless encounters and partings with you and your feelings,
真実 人は生きる意味を見つける
truth: people find the meaning of life.
狂い咲けよ 咲き誇れ 闘志の華よ
Bloom wildly, bloom in pride, O flowers of fighting spirit!
戦の地に降り立つ夢
A dream of stepping down onto the battlefield,
大輪の炎 闇を蹴散らして
kicking away the darkness with a great blossom of flame.
勝利を 勇気と熱を 縦に掴め
Seize victory with courage and passion as your shield!
連れて行こう 辿り着く 金色の空
Let's go forth, reaching the golden sky.
笑顔を育む大地へ
To the land that nurtures smiles,
夜はいずれ去り 朝が訪れる
night will eventually depart and morning will come.
全てを越えて 君の愛 叶う
Surpassing everything, your love will come true.
Welcome to this crazy time
このイカれた時代へようこそ君は
welcome to this crazy era, you are
tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy
a tough boy, tough boy, tough boy, tough boy!
まともな奴ほど feel so bad
The more decent you are, the more you feel so bad.
正気でいられるなんて運がイイぜ you
Being able to stay sane means you're lucky, you
tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy
時はまさに世紀末
Time is truly the end of the century.
澱んだ街角で僕らは出会った
We met on a stagnant street corner.
Keep you burning 駆け抜けて
Keep you burning, running through
この腐敗と自由と暴力のまっただなか
in the midst of this corruption, freedom, and violence.
No boy no cry 悲しみは
No boy, no cry, sadness is
絶望じゃなくて明日のマニフェスト
not despair, but tomorrow's manifesto.
We are living
living in the eighties
We still fight
fighting in the eighties
どこもかしこも傷だらけ
Scratches everywhere,
うずくまってないでってはじまらないから
It doesn't start if you just crouch and cry,
tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy
どっちを向いても feel so sad
Feel so sad no matter which way you look,
だけど死には至らない
But it won't lead to death,
気分はどうだい?
How do you feel?
tough boy tough boy tough boy tough boy
ここは永遠のロックランド
This is eternal rockland,
拳を握りしめ僕らは出会った
We met clenching our fists,
Keep you burning 駆け抜けて
Keep you burning, running through,
この狂気と希望と幻滅のまっただなか
In the middle of this madness, hope, and disillusionment,
NO BOY NO CRY 進まなきゃ
No boy, no cry, I have to move on,
勢いを増した向かい風の中を
Through the headwind that gained more momentum,
We are living, living in the eighties / We still fight, fighting in the eighties
野うさぎ討伐戦 突入！
Wild Rabbit Subjugation Battle: Breakthrough!
野うさぎ 1体目
Wild Rabbit #1
これからボクを狩りに来てもらうよ？
You're gonna come hunt me down now, right?
お前たちのヒーローは超うさぎがいただくぺこ！
Super Rabbit is gonna take your heroes, peko!
プッシュぺこ！ごちそうさまでした！
Push, peko! Thanks for the meal!
完全撃破
Completely Defeated!
This is a fate that brought us here watch my long shot
Feel like I am falling into the flame of lies / Tell me what do you want from me
Trying not to step back to where I used to belong / Looking for the escape from pain
I will cross my fingers hoping not to be sacrificed / 約束したんだ 君とその希望に
I will cross my fingers hoping not to be sacrificed / That is the promise I made with you, and to that hope
Get in the raid / Get ready for the time to come
浮かび上がるシルエット 追いかけ
Chasing the silhouette that appears on the surface
Drop down the reason why I'm standing here alone
Maybe it's already too late to regain
運命としてかかげた灯を 失わないで
Don't lose the light held up as fate, ever again
What if I could right my wrongs and save you from the pain / It's not enough
It's not enough for me to break the rule upon this world
I will never gonna leave you / Never wanna lose you / We'll make it in the end
Not backing down for real
I won't trace someone else's life
I know who I am
Blame me if I mess up anything,
Take the risk of everything,
Just to find this cruel world.
夢も願いも 全て賭けてく
Risking all my dreams and wishes,
影を求めて
seeking the shadows.
I will cross my fingers hoping not to be sacrificed,
If you've understood that you can't somehow keep up with me,
Get in a flurry, get ready for the time to come.
夢を追いかけて そっと追いかけて
Chasing dreams, softly chasing them...
Don't be afraid to be yourself,
It's all you.
何度だっていいんだ 覚悟してんだ全て
No matter how many times, I'm prepared for everything.
守ると決めたよ
I've decided to protect you.
君がいるから
Because you are here.
絡み合う未来を この手で変えてみせるとして
If I'm to change our intertwined future with my own hands,
すべきことは 分かっているから
I know what I have to do.
Take this pain away from me,
この胸の奥底に乗せて
carrying it deep within my chest.
There's no way I can fail me, go get that wish you've ever had!
There's no way I can fail, go get that wish you've ever had!
Got down the reason why I'm standing near alone,
Maybe it's already too late to regain.
夢を閉じて掲げた日を失さないで
Don't lose the day you held up with closed dreams.
Face yourself, don't forget this is your fate.
What if I could break my wrongs and save you from the pain?
It's not enough, it's not enough for me
To break the rule upon this world!
to break the rules upon this world!
I will never gonna leave you, never wanna lose you,
I'll make it in the end!
Not backing down for real,
I won't chase someone else's life.
I know who I am.
待っていたのは この瞬間
This is the moment we've been waiting for!
BONUS確定！
Bonus Confirmed!
錬金術師たちが
The alchemists...
一撃で…
with a single blow...
紅色のフリューゲル
Crimson Fluegel
聞こえますか
Can you hear it?
奏で広がる無数の
Countless melodies spreading out,
手に解き放て
unleash them into your hands.
響き渡る声は
The echoing voices
命始まる脈動
are the pulse where life begins.
愛を突き上げて
Thrust your love upward!
はるか彼方
Far into the distance,
音楽となったあの日の風は
the wind of that day that became music
泣いて 笑って やがて伝え紡ぐ
cries, laughs, and soon weaves its tale.
鼓動を歌にした そして夢は開くよ
Turning the heartbeat into a song, our dreams will open up.
見たことない世界の果てへ
To the edge of a world never seen before,
Yes, just believe
神様も知らない ヒカリで歴史を創ろう
Let's create history with a light unknown even to gods.
不死なる太陽 未来照らす
The immortal sun illuminates the future.
一緒に飛ばないか？
Shall we fly together?
涙で濡れた羽を 重くして
With wings soaked in tears, making them heavy,
羽ばたけない日は Wish
on days when you cannot fly, Wish
その右手に添えよう 描くチカラを
Let's lend a hand to that right hand, the power to draw,
鳥のように はためき合うよ Singing heart
like birds, fluttering together, Singing heart
いつかの日にか 分かる時が来るから ずっと忘れない
Because a time will come when you'll understand someday, I'll never forget.
その時には こころの有るがままに 笑顔 忘れない
At that time, just as your heart desires, never forgetting a smile,
言葉で まだ見ぬ地平の先 強く強く結んで
with words, beyond the unseen horizon, binding strongly,
繋がり合おう
let's connect together.
今舞う 七色の翼 そして生きる今を
Now dance, wings of seven colors, and live in the present,
見たことない明日の先へ
toward the beyond of an unseen tomorrow.
Yes, just believe 1000年後の今日も
Yes, just believe, even 1,000 years from today,
生まれ変わって 歌いたい 暖かいよ この温もり
I want to be reborn and sing. It's warm, this warmth.
絶対離さない 運命なんて
I will never let go, fate itself
変えられない 物語は自分にあるじゃん
cannot be changed; our story is within ourselves.
逃げ出したくなったら 空を見上げよう
If you ever want to run away, look up at the sky.
勇気こそが輝くんだよ Singing star
Courage is what truly shines, Singing star.
遥かかなた 星が音楽となったかの日
Far away, on the day when stars became music,
たぶん共に出逢い 響き神話のひとつように紡いだ
perhaps we met together, resonating and weaving like a myth.
見たことない世界の果てへ
To the edge of a world we've never seen.
Yes, just believe
神様も知らない ヒカリで歴史を作ろう
let's create history with a light unknown even to gods.
不死なる太陽 未来照らす
The immortal sun illuminates the future.
一緒に飛ばないか？
Shall we fly together?
涙で濡れた羽を重くして羽ばたけない日は Wish
On days when wings soaked in tears are too heavy to fly, Wish
旋律は溶け合って シンフォニーへと
Melodies melt together into a symphony.
鳥のように はためき合うよ Singing heart
Like birds, fluttering together, Singing heart
虹はかかる すべては夢と共に
A rainbow appears; everything is together with our dreams.
野うさぎ剣を押し込め！
Push in the Field Rabbit Sword!
行け 疾風のごとく
Go, like a gale,
宿命の剣士よ
O swordsman of destiny!
闇にまぎれて
Lost in the darkness,
牙狼 -SAVIOR IN THE DARK-
GARO -SAVIOR IN THE DARK-
何故 戦うのか
why do you fight?
のが それは剣に聞け
What is that? That is the sword of destiny.
行け 疾風のごとく 宿命の剣士よ
Go, like a tempest, O fateful swordsman!
闇にまぎれて 何故 戦うのか
Why do you fight, swallowed by the darkness?
正義だとか愛など 俺は追いかけない
I chase neither justice nor love.
闇に生まれ 闇に忍び 闇を切り裂く
Born in the dark, creeping through the dark, cutting through the dark.
遥かな古から 受け継いだ使命だから
Because it's a mission passed down from ancient times.
行け! 疾風のごとく 魔戒の剣士よ
Go! Like a tempest, O magical swordsman!
月満つる夜に 金色になれ
Turn golden on a moonlit night.
雄々しき姿の 孤高な戦士よ
O stalwart, solitary warrior!
魂を込めた 怒りの刃叩きつけて
Infusing your soul, striking with the blade of wrath,
時代に輝け 牙狼!
shine through the ages, Garo!
いつの日か おまえには わかってほしい
I want you to understand someday.
戦いだけに生きた 俺の胸の内を
Inside the chest of one who lived only for battle,
愛に背く 愛を憎み 愛を求める
I spurn love, curse love, yet crave love.
わずかな安らぎさえ 打ち捨てた誓いだけど
Even a sliver of comfort was a vow I cast aside.
立て! 修羅のごとく 魔戒の剣士よ
Stand up! Like Shura, O magical swordsman!
運命の歌の 命ずるままに
As the song of fate commands,
月夜に輝く 高貴な戦士よ
shine on the moonlit night, O lofty warrior!
迫り来る影を 一網打尽 叩き斬って
Strike down the approaching shadows with a single sweep,
気高く吠えろ 牙狼!
and howl nobly, Garo!
いつの日か おまえには わかってほしい
I want you to understand someday.
戦いだけに生きた 俺の胸の内を
Inside the chest of one who lived only for battle,
愛に背く 愛を憎み 愛を求める
I spurn love, curse love, yet crave love.
わずかな安らぎさえ 打ち捨てた誓いだけど
Even a sliver of comfort was a vow I cast aside.
立て! 修羅のごとく 魔戒の剣士よ
Stand up! Like Shura, O magical swordsman!
運命の歌の 命ずるままに
As the song of fate commands,
月夜に輝く 高貴な戦士よ
shine on the moonlit night, O lofty warrior!
迫り来る影を 一網打尽 叩き斬って
Strike down the approaching shadows with a single sweep,
気高く吠えろ 牙狼!
and howl nobly, Garo!
行け 疾風のごとく 宿命の剣士よ
Go, like a tempest, O fateful swordsman!
闇にまぎれて 何故 戦うのか
Why fight, swallowed by the darkness?
正義だとか愛など 俺は追いかけない
I chase neither justice nor love.
闇に生まれ 闇に忍び 闇を切り裂く
Born in the dark, creeping through the dark, cutting through the dark.
遥かな古から 受け継いだ使命だから
Because it's a mission passed down from ancient times.
行け! 疾風のごとく 魔戒の剣士よ
Go! Like a tempest, O magical swordsman!
月満つる夜に 金色になれ
Turn golden on a moonlit night.
雄々しき姿の 孤高な戦士よ
O stalwart, solitary warrior!
魂を込めた 怒りの刃叩きつけて
Infusing your soul, striking with the blade of wrath,
時代に輝け 牙狼!
shine through the ages, Garo!
行け 疾風のごとく 宿命の剣士よ
Go, like a tempest, O fateful swordsman!
闇にまぎれて 何故 戦うのか
Why fight, swallowed by the darkness?
正義だとか愛など 俺は追いかけない
I chase neither justice nor love.
闇に生まれ 闇に忍び 闇を切り裂く
Born in the dark, creeping through the dark, cutting through the dark.
遥かな古から 受け継いだ使命だから
Because it's a mission passed down from ancient times.
行け! 疾風のごとく 魔戒の剣士よ
Go! Like a tempest, O magical swordsman!
月満つる夜に 金色になれ
Turn golden on a moonlit night.
雄々しき姿の 孤高な戦士よ
O stalwart, solitary warrior!
魂を込めた 怒りの刃叩きつけて
Infusing your soul, striking with the blade of wrath,
時代に輝け 牙狼!
shine through the ages, Garo!
行け 疾風のごとく 宿命の剣士よ
Go, like a tempest, O fateful swordsman!
闇にまぎれて 何故 戦うのか
Why fight, swallowed by the darkness?
正義だとか愛など 俺は追いかけない
I chase neither justice nor love.
闇に生まれ 闇に忍び 闇を切り裂く
Born in the dark, creeping through the dark, cutting through the dark.
遥かな古から 受け継いだ使命だから
Because it's a mission passed down from ancient times.
行け! 疾風のごとく 魔戒の剣士よ
Go! Like a tempest, O magical swordsman!
今度こそ 君だけは 幸せにしてみせるぺこ!
This time for sure, I'll make you happy, peko!
ボーナス確定
Bonus confirmed!
悲しい日びが 化石に 変わるよ
Kanashii hibi ga kaseki ni kawaru yo
もうすぐ あなたの その 痛みを
mou sugu anata no sono itami o
眠りの 森へ と ひそやかに 導いてあげる
nemuri no mori e to hisoyaka ni michibiite ageru
おやすみ すべてに 一途すぎた 迷い子たち
Oyasumi subete ni ichizu sugita mayoi gotachi
はがゆさが 夢に 進化する 日まで
hagayusa ga yume ni shinka suru hi made
生命は まぶしい 朝を 待っている
Inochi wa mabushii asa o matte iru
最後の 懺悔も かなわ ないなら
Saigo no zange mo kanawanai nara
いつか 時代の 夜が 明ける
Itsuka jidai no yoru ga akeru
世界よ まぶたを 閉じて
Sekai yo mabuta o tojite
生命は 目覚めて 時を 紡ぎだす
Inochi wa mezamete toki o tsumugidasu
あなたの 証拠を さかのぼるように
Anata no shouko o sakanoboru you ni
そして 光が 胸に 届く
Soshite hikari ga mune ni todoku
心よ 原始に 戻れ
Kokoro yo genshi ni modore
涙の岸で ずっとたたずんだ 気持ちを
Namida no kishi de zutto tatazunda kigochi o
やさしく 包むように 秘密の薬が
yasashiku tsumu you ni himitsu no kusuri ga
思い出の沖へと 運ぶよ
omoide no oki e to hakobu yo
おやすみ モラルに 汚れていた 指も耳も
Oyasumi moraru ni yogorete ita yubi mo mimi mo
この腕の中で もう眠りなさい
kono ude no naka de mou nemuri nasai
生命は まぶしい 朝を 待っている
Inochi wa mabushii asa o matte iru
破れた 聖書を 抱きしめるより
Yabureta seisho o dakishimeru yori
いつか 時代の 夜が 明ける
Itsuka jidai no yoru ga akeru
あなたよ 祈りを 捨てて
Anata yo inori o sutete
生命は 目覚めて 時を 紡ぎだす
Inochi wa mezamete toki o tsumugidasu
自然のルールに その身をまかせ
Shizen no ruuru ni sono mi o makase
そして 光が 胸に 届く
Soshite hikari ga mune ni todoku
心よ 原始に 戻れ
Kokoro yo genshi ni modore
生命は まぶしい 朝を 待っている
Inochi wa mabushii asa o matte iru
最後の 懺悔も かなわ ないなら
Saigo no zange mo kanawanai nara
いつか 時代の 夜が 明ける
Itsuka jidai no yoru ga akeru
世界よ まぶたを 閉じて
Sekai yo mabuta o tojite
生命は 目覚めて 時を 紡ぎだす
Inochi wa mezamete toki o tsumugidasu
あなたの 証拠を さかのぼるように
Anata no shouko o sakanoboru you ni
そして 光が 胸に 届く
Soshite hikari ga mune ni todoku
心よ 原始に 戻れ
Kokoro yo genshi ni modore
ノエル、マリン、みんな どこ行っちゃったペコなの？
Noel, Marine, everyone, where did you go, Pekora?
まあ、ペコラの3Dライブならなんとかなるような、きっと。
Well, Pekora's solo 3D live will probably work out somehow, right?
ということで ここまでは たくさんのゲストの皆さん と たくさんの曲を
So, up until now, we've had lots of guest singers and lots of songs...
お届けしましたが！ みんなよろしくね！
We've performed them! Everyone, please—
おっとか、会えましたか?
Oops, did we connect?
楽しんでくれてますか?
Are you enjoying yourselves?
最後にもね、1曲ペコラまた歌いますのでそちらもお楽しみにということで、
And finally, I'll be singing another song, so please look forward to that as well!
ここからはグッズ紹介!
From here on, it's the goods introduction!
お、ペコっちゃ!
Oh, Pekoccha!
ということは?
Which means?
引き当てた! 引き当てた!
You pulled it! You pulled it!
ということで、うさぎペコラ活動6周年記念グッズを紹介するぺこ!
With that said, I'll be introducing Usada Pekora's 6th anniversary commemorative goods, peko!
まずは1つ目はこちらから!
First up, the first item is right here!
どーん！ぺこら推し法被！
Ta-da! The Pekora-oshi happi coat!
こちらはゆきはぐれ先生に書いていただきました! もうね、着るだけで推しをアピールできるイベントでも来てきてほしいペコです! めちゃめちゃかわいいハッピペコなので是非ともよろーら!
This was designed by Yuki Hagure-sensei! Just wearing it lets you rep your oshi, and I'd love for you to wear it to events too! It's super cute, so please check it out!
そして2つ目は、こちら! どーん!
And the second item is right here, ta-da!
な、な、な、なんとついにペコラマミーも映っているグッズが出てしまいました! こちらラバーマットです!
Unbelievable, merchandise featuring Pekora Mommy has finally been released! This is a rubber mat!
イラストはヒコサンにお願いしております! テーマはカジノのうさだけぺこらとペコラマミーです!
The illustration is by Hikosansan! The theme is casino Usada Pekora and Pekora Mommy!
ついにでてしまった! ま、マミー方だからね、是非ともペコラマミー大好きな人もお手に取ってもらえると嬉しいペコです。
It's finally out! Since it features Mommy, I'd be so happy if everyone who loves Pekora Mommy could grab one too.
そしてラバーマットがあるということは? 3つ目は? こちら!
And since we have a rubber mat, what does that mean? The third item is right here!
はい、カードスリーブもちゃんとあるペコです!
Yes, we also have card sleeves properly available, peko!
60枚入りでね、イラストは先ほどと同じヒコサンにお願いしております。
It comes in a pack of 60, with illustrations by Hikosan, just like before.
なんとこちら、ホロカでも使えますので、ぜひともホロカで遊んでる方は使っていただけると嬉しいペコです!
And guess what, you can even use these in Holoca! So I'd be super happy if anyone playing Holoca would use them!
そして4つ目は、こちら! かわいいね、ペコラぬいぐるみキーホルダー!
And the fourth item is right here! So cute, a Pekora plush keychain!
カバンにつけてもよし、旅行先に持ってくのもよしの持ち運びやすいサイズのぬいぐるみとなって るぺこ!
It's a portable-sized plushie that's great to attach to your bag or bring along on trips, peko!
こちらなんとフルセット購入の特典がございます!
And there is a special bonus for purchasing the full set!
数量限定で直筆サイン入りポストカードがあります!
A limited quantity includes a postcard with an autograph!
そしてね、通常バージョンは箔押し複製サイン入りのポストカードとなってまして、はぐれ先生のはっぴのイラストとなっております!
And the regular version features a foil-stamped replica signed postcard with Hagure-sensei's happi illustration!
是非ともジャンジャンバリバリ買ってぺこ!
Be sure to buy as many as you want, peko!
それでは最後は何の曲かな? お楽しみに!
Now, what could the final song be? Look forward to it!
係員をお呼びください。
Please call an attendant.
ちょっと!
Hey!
ライブできない、ライブできない! ちょっとちょーだい!
I can't do the live! Hey, give it here!
おい監視カメラ見えてんぞ、お前コラ!
Hey, I can see the security camera, you bastard!
直して早く! ライブできないじゃねえかよ!
Fix it quickly! I can't do my concert!
叩いたって直るわけねえだろ! 叩いて直るわけないだろ! ちょっと!
Hitting it isn't going to fix anything! There's no way hitting it will fix it! Come on!
仮想の世に生まれ 生きること
Born into a virtual world and living,
即ち 戦い 勝つこと
That is, fighting and winning,
時代と戦い 己が宿命と戦い
Fighting against the era, fighting against one's destiny,
己自身に打ち勝つ いつもの世も大差はなし
Conquering oneself, no era is all that different.
人の生き様が一瞬の煌めきが
The way people live, that momentary flash,
歴史を紡いでいく 今こそ胸に刻め
Weaving history, carve it into your chest right now,
我が生き様を 永遠に語り継げ
Our way of life, pass down the tale forever,
兎田の魂を 戦いの炎を
Usada's soul, the flames of battle,
灯して見せよ
Kindle them and show the world!
Are you ready?
Shall We Dance? 始めよう
Shall we dance? Let's begin,
勝利の祝杯上げる前に
Before raising the toast of victory,
Relax Your Body 深呼吸
Relax your body, take a deep breath,
そうすりゃだんだん高まる Passion Force
That way, your passion force will gradually rise.
膝をもっと引き上げたら右手を開けYEAH!
If you lift your knees high, raise your right hand YEAH!
○○○○○六文銭
Five-mon, six-mon, Sanada's Six Coins!
まだまだいけるはずさ もっともっともっともっともっと！
You can still go further, more and more and more!
Take A Chance! Take A Chance! 勝利のために Take A Chance! Take A Chance! Well Done!
Take A Chance! For victory, Take A Chance! Well Done!
SANADA DA DANCE
日ノ本一のつわもの
Japan's finest warrior!
CHA RA CHA CHA CHA
不死身だぜ
You're immortal!
SANADA DA DANCE
急げ夜が明ける前に
Hurry before the night breaks!
CHA RA CHA CHA
赤く赤く備えたなら
If you prepare blazing red,
踊れ！歌え！SANADA DANCE 戦CISE
Dance! Sing! SANADA DANCE Sen-CISE!
Wow Wow Wow...
It's Cypher time
Close your eyes 瞑想
Close your eyes, meditate
Don't think... Feel 感覚研ぎ澄ませたなら高まる
Don't think... Feel, when your senses are sharpened, you rise higher
Passion Force Y.U.K.I.M.U.R.A
フロントキックでツイストかまして視線は下げずに、ハイポーズ！
Throw a front kick with a twist, keep your eyes up, high pose!
回って回ってブンブン回って回転スピード増し増し！
Spin and spin, whirring around, boosting the spin speed!
勢いづけでそうさ もっともっともっともっともっと！
Just like that, gain momentum, more and more and more!
Change the world! Change the world! Do or Do not! There is no try!
Change the world! Do or Do not! There is no try!
SANADA DA DANCE
ハート燃やして不夜城
Burn your heart in the sleepless city
CHA RA CHA CHA CHA... 不死身だぜ
CHA RA CHA CHA CHA... You're immortal!
SANADA DA DANCE
心踊らせるために
To make your heart dance
CHA RA CHA CHA CHA CHANCE
熱く熱く構えたなら
If you take a burning hot stance,
走れ！回れ！しゃがめ！伸ばせ！
Run! Spin! Crouch! Stretch!
空に叫べ！SANADA DANCE 戦CISE
Shout to the sky! SANADA DANCE Sen-CISE!
Wow Wow Wow...
苦しい時や辛い時には 体動かせよ SANADA DANCE
When times are tough or painful, move your body, SANADA DANCE
天上天下唯我独尊 みんなで踊ろう SANADA DANCE Let's Go!
I alone am honored in heaven and earth, let's dance together SANADA DANCE Let's Go!
Take A Chance! Change the world!
深呼吸 Ba Hoooooo!
Take a deep breath, Ba Hoooooo!
本日も最終最後の時間まで、うさぎぺこら6周年ライブにお付き合いいただきまして、誠にありがとうございました。
Thank you very much for joining us for Usada Pekora's 6th Anniversary Live, all the way until the very end today.
はい、ありがとうございました。ありがとうございました。
Yes, thank you very much. Thank you very much.
残念ではございますが、まもなく本日のライブはすべて終了とさせていただきます。
We regret to announce that today's live stream will soon be coming to an end.
メンバーシップカードをお持ちのお客さまにご案内申し上げます。
We have an announcement for customers who hold membership cards.
メンバーシップカードをお持ちの方は、この後の10時15分より行われるアンコールライブにもご参加いただけます。
Holders of membership cards can also participate in the encore live starting at 10:15 PM.
お持ちでない方もまだ間に合いますので、この機会にぜひご加入ください。
Even if you don't have one yet, you still have time, so please consider joining us.
またグッズ販売の方もまもなくカートオープンとなります。10時10分より販売となりますので、ご購乳ご検討の皆様は販売サイトにてご購入ください。
Also, merchandise sales will open shortly. Sales start at 10:10 PM, so please purchase via the sales site if you're interested.
明日のご案内を申し上げます。
Here is the announcement for tomorrow.
明日の営業は通常通り夜から配信を行います。明日もうさぎぺこらはりきってまいりますので、ご来店お待ちしております。
Tomorrow's business will start from the evening as usual. Usada Pekora will be doing her best tomorrow too, so we look forward to your visit.
大変なごり惜しくはございますが、本日はこれにてライブ終了とさせていただきます。
It is with great regret, but we will conclude today's live performance with this.
最終最後までお付き合いいただき、ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much for staying with us until the very end.
USADA PEKORA 3D LIVE ぺこB RUSH!!
[USADA PEKORA 3D LIVE PEKO-B RUSH!!]